Guide to The Fugs Archive MSS.013
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fugs Archive
circa 1963-1971, 2010-2017
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fugs (Musical group)
MSS.013
0.75 Linear Feet in 2 boxes
4 audiocassettes
1 websites in 1 archived website.
The Fugs Archive is a part of the Avant Garde Collection at Fales Library, New York University. The Fugs Archive is a collection of correspondence and manuscripts about band members Ed Sanders, Tuli Kupferberg, and Ken Weaver. Materials are arranged in alphabetical and chronological order.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Fugs Archive was purchased from Richard Aaron of Am Here Books in February 1975. The accession number associated with this collection is 1975.013.
http://www.thefugs.com/ was initially selected by Tamiment curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2010 as part of the Arts and Cultural Left Web Archive. In November 2015, the website was migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2017, http://www.thefugs.com/ was transferred to Fales Library.
Arrangement
The Fugs Archive is arranged in alphabetical and chronological order and arranged into three series:
Series I: Correspondence, Manuscripts, Flyers, Newsclipping and Publications
Series II: Audio
Series III: Archived Website
Historical Note
The Fugs, a group of poet-musicians, were virtually conceived and developed on the off-Broadway stage. They performed first at the Bridge Theater. After a run of a full two weeks, Ed Sanders, poet, editor, owner of the fabled Peace Eye Book Store and leader of the group, decided the show was ready for a cross-country tour. In a borrowed Volkswagen bus, the Fugs stormed suprised academies from the Kinsey Institute in Bloomington, Indiana to the University of Kansas and on to Berkeley.
The Fugs satirized everything from political involvement and patriotism to rock and roll, from war and hate to super-abundant love. The Fugs performed about 15 of their 110 songs per show and presented 12 shows a week during their theater runs. Rather than object to the rigor of the long run, they became more and more intrigued by the possibibilities of the theater through constantly changing and adding to their repertoire. The Fugs were an ever-evolving improvisational review.
The Fugs consisted of three members: Tuli Kupferberg, native New Yorker and "one of the leading Anarchist theorists of our time," Ken Weaver, humorist and poet, and Ed Sanders, poet and leader of the group.
Scope and Content Note
The Fugs Archive consists of correspondence, manuscripts, flyers, newsclippings, and publications dating between 1963-1971. Also includes their archived website collected from 2010-2017.
Separated Material
Several periodicals and chapbooks have been separated from the Fugs Archive and cataloged. These periodicals and chapbooks are searchable in Bobcat. Three posters have been removed from the collection and placed in the map case. These posters are listed at the end of the Box and Folder List.
Rock musicians.; Announcements.; Correspondence.; Rock music.; Rock groups.; Performance art.; Experimental theater -- 20th century; Photographs.; Avant-garde (Aesthetics); American poetry -- 20th century.; Poets, American -- 20th century.; Manuscripts for publication.; Fliers (printed matter); Posters.; Protest songs -- United States.; Folk-rock music -- New York (State) -- New York; Weaver, Ken, 1940-; Kupferberg, Tuli; Sanders, Ed
- Series I: Correspondence, Manuscripts, Flyers, Newsclippings, and Publications
  Scope and Contents note
  Series 1 contains 1 box of correspondence and manuscripts written by the Fugs, various flyers, newsclippings and publications.
  - List of archive, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biography, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and manuscripts: Kupferberg, Tuli, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and manuscripts: Sanders, Ed, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and manuscripts: Weaver, Ken, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Announcements regarding Ed Sanders, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Archive 76: The Marijuana Newsletter, Issue 2; March 15, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Separated Materials Note
    The Marijuana Newsletter has been removed to the Fales stacks. It can be located in the NYU Bobcat online catalog.
  - Archive 80: A Valorium edition of the entire extant works of Thales, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Archive 84: Maxims and aphorisms from the letters of D.H. Lawrence, compiled by Marguerite Harris, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Archive 95, 97, 98: Ed Sanders catalogues 3, 4.5, 6 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ESP-Disk order form, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Fugs flip, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Flyers, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Logo, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photo, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Poets at the Metro, vol. VIII, November 1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Transatlantic news and transatlantic letters, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Sanders truckstop [bio], undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Newsclips, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Newsclip composit, [1966] (Box Shared Fales 080, Folder 11)
  - The Fugs poster regarding ESP disk--black and white, undated (Box Shared Fales 080, Folder 11)
  - The Fugs poster regarding ESP disk--color, undated (Box Shared Fales 080, Folder 11)
- Series II: Audio
  - Ed Sanders Interview, 1968-10-01; 2018-02; cuid6288 (Box 2, Reel cuid6288, E-records fales_MSS013, E-records fales_MSS013_cuid6288)
    Scope and Contents
    An audio recording of an interview with Fugs member, Ed Sanders, that occured in London in 1968.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Original format: 1/4" Open Reel Audio, Duration: 66 min.
  - Ken Weaver, Taken from Notebooks [Reel 1], 1969-02-06; 2018-02; cuid6289 (Box 2, Reel cuid6289, E-records fales_MSS013, E-records fales_MSS013_cuid6289)
    An audio recording of Fugs member, Ken Weaver, titled "Taken from notebooks," on February 6th, 1969, recorded in New York City from 6pm-6:30pm.
    Original format: 1/4" Open Reel Audio, Duration: 49 min.
  - Ken Weaver, Cinematograph Montage, El Campo Texas High School Stories [Reel 2], undated; 2018-02; cuid6290 (Box 2, Reel cuid6290, E-records fales_MSS013, E-records cuid6290)
  - Ken Weaver, American TV Stories, The Hog Man [Reel 3], 1969-02-06; 2018-02; cuid6291 (Box 2, Reel cuid6291, E-records fales_MSS013, E-records fales_MSS013_cuid6291)
    General
    Recorded at 9:45pm on February 6th, 1969.
    Original format: 1/4" Open Reel Audio, Duration: 50 min.
- Series III: Archived Website, July 2010-November 2017; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored with the permission of the content owner. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.thefugs.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  The Fugs, a group of poet-musicians, was founded in New York City's East Village in early 1965 by Ed Sanders, Ken Weaver, and Tuli Kupferberg (1923-2010). The website contains biographies of their members, a history of the group, information on their albums, music commentary, reunion shows, and information about Kupferberg's illness and death in 2010.